Baddi (Solan district), Himachal Pradesh

Ph: 8290542509

Email: bibashwanc@gmail.com

Bibashwan Chatterjee

Content development, copywriting, and SEO-based creative content marketing learner with experience of 4.5+ years. I have worked in roles involving content writing, ghostwriting, guest posting, on-page and off-page SEO, proofreading, blogging, content editing, copywriting, and other tasks related to marketing and business development via content creation.

SKILLS

Content-based advertising (writing for SEO), blogging, copywriting (digital and social media), creative and technical content writing, public relations and client interaction, content editing, PR, British & American English proficiency

SOFTWARE

Microsoft Word, Canva, Google (Docs, Sheets, and Slides), WordPress, and Microsoft PowerPoint

EXPERIENCE

- **1. Zapbuild, Virtual** Sales and Marketing May 2020 July 2020
- Worked on managing outbound and inbound calls from the USA regarding DOT compliance
- Worked as a sales executive to aid clients with yearly DOT services
- 2. Syavi Publishing House (FanatiXx branch), Bangalore Content Manager and Language Editor
 July 2020 April 2021
- Worked with 'FanatiXx' and 'Spectrum of Thoughts' for world-record anthology projects as a co-author
- Content writing and publishing for various titles
- Training budding writers to write and post daily on Instagram (short creative write-ups)
- **3. askanydifference.com** Ghostwriter (technical content and blogs) July 2021 Jan 2022
- Internship and work profile offered by askanydifference.com

- Ghostwriting and content publishing via WordPress
- Submission of SEO-optimized technical content within a structured format and deadlines

4. differentiatebetween.com — Editor

Jan 2022 - April 2022

- Guided and managed a team of 25 to 30 content writers for daily content posting
- Daily tasks included; content selection, image editing, proofreading, and content posting along with improving the SEO-based content written by my team
- Manage the entire website and monitor the KPI of individual content writers

5. Funnel Truffle — Content Writer

May 2022 - June 2022

- Working on articles and blogs based on real estate-related niche
- Researching US-based realtor websites and services and copywriting for the same
- Writing blogs for the USA and Canadian real estate markets and content marketing

6. Internshala — Client Interaction and Proofreading June 2022 - June 2023

- Monitoring internship posts and job posts' credibility and proofreading before publishing the content on Internshala's website
- Interacting with clients and solving client issues
- Approving the client's credibility and documentation before publishing their internship requirements on Internshala's website

7. McCann Worldgroup, Gurugram — Copywriting intern

July 2023 - August 2023

- Copywriting for brands including Flipkart Wholesale, Bajaj, Hero, LIC, Lloyd, Alpenliebe, Wildstone, Gyan Dairy, Air India, and many more.
- Copywriting for BTL communication

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Chandigarh University, BAJMC (Bachelor of Arts in Journalism and Mass Communication)

2019 - 2022, Chandigarh, Mohali

Completed Graduation from CU with a semestral specialization in Public Relations: CGPA= 8.01

Jagran Lakecity University, MAAPR (Masters of Arts in Advertising and Public Relations)

2022 - Pursuing, Bhopal

Courses and Workshops

- Completed 1-month workshop-cum-internship from FanatiXx publications on anthology writing, book compiling, short story writing and creative writing for novels and storybooks
- Interned as a Digital Marketing and SEO-based content writer and copywriter for 3 months at Abbey Edge India Pvt Ltd. (Jan 2022 to April 2022), Chandigarh. Worked for the SEO and content team to provide ad copy pieces, blogs, SEO descriptions, and classified ads on tentative deadlines along with pooling creative advertising and marketing ideas for the brand
- Interned with askanydifference.com on ghostwriting, SEO-optimized content creation, and blogging
- Completed PR and Mass Communication (Intermediate and Advanced) online course from saylor.org
- Completed Digital Marketing and IT additional course from Google Garage

Awards and Contributions

- Published anthologies for world record nominations from FanatiXx and Spectrum of Thoughts
- Media Mela, Punjab Khalsa College Association fest, Advertisement designing 2nd rank in Inter-College competition
- Content edited and published for the independent magazine series "India Unveiled" in Bachelor's of Journalism and Mass Communication from Chandigarh University
- Limca World Records and Indian World Records recognized anthology projects for which I received certificates as a co-author
- Volunteered in JLU Media Fest 2023 and escorted the chief guest

Hobbies

Reading, binging movies and anime, soccer, listening to audiobooks, clicking and editing photos of nature, abstract and material subjects.

Link of Certificates

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1pJvUEKLz7q02M8VpcWms98fWWKAlyROK?usp=sharing